[Horse hooves cloping]
[MOBLIT]
The report was right.
The whole village
has been devastated.
But there's not a drop of blood,
let alone any bodies.
It's eerie. Still,
maybe they got out?
It's not unheard of.
In theory, I suppose.
But then the question
becomes why Titans
would smash up empty houses?
Bit difficult to believe.
What's more, how far
were these people
hoping to get by
leaving their horses here?
That's a good point.
So what do you think happened?
Moblit, I found it! Look!
There you are.
[MALE SOLDIER 35B] You, uh...
you should see this.
[MOBLIT] A portrait of Conny
Springer's parents, I presume?
Seems very likely, sir.
[MOBLIT and SOLDIERS gasp]
It's alive!
No! Stand down!
[MOBLIT gasps]
What the hell is going on?
♪ Opening Song ♪
[REINER] It's your call.
What's it gonna be?
Is it Christa's future?
Or your own petty existence?
Hey! Talk!
Who's the real enemy here?
Tell me!
[YMIR sighs]
--Couldn't say.
--[EREN grunts]
[REINER] All right, then.
Sorry, Eren.
[Distant gunshot]
[REINER]
You're kidding.
[BERTHOLDT] The Scouts
are here? Already?
Son of a bitch!
Talk to me, Reiner.
What are you right now?
A warrior. Calm down.
Do you really think it's
wise for us to trust Ymir?
Even though she's the one
who devoured Marcel?
Sure. Don't you see?
We have a handle
on her motives.
When she turned human again,
odds are she just
wandered around aimlessly only
giving a damn about herself.
But then Christa
came into the picture.
That's the kind of girl that
can change your whole world.
We need her, and not
just because she's cute.
The people she comes from
are an important family
within the church.
Plus, suppose Eren's
not the coordinate?
Our job wouldn't be over.
If it comes to that,
having Christa around
will make the search
a lot easier.
[Gasps]
They're close.
[EREN]
What are they talking about?
They still plan on clearing out
before sundown or not?
Please, let's just be done.
The next time we come,
we'll take all three.
Annie, Christa, and that.
It'll be clean and simple.
Then we won't have
to come here anymore.
Right. And we'll have
completed our damn mission.
Just do me a favor, huh?
Once we're home, try telling
Annie how you really feel.
What's that
supposed to mean?
Ugh. Come on.
I've seen the way
you stare at her.
I don't stare!
Bertholdt, please,
life's short enough as it is.
Just go for it. Besides,
you're both killers
so she understands
where your head is.
What're you two doing now?
I thought we were
waiting till dark.
There's been a slight
change of plans.
I'm gonna ask you nicely not
to try to put up a fight.
Easy. There's no need
for us to get all violent.
It's not like I can
resist like this.
I mean, take a look at me.
Just, calm down, okay?
[EREN grunts]
Die! Die! Die! Die!
Die, you evil--!
[REINER grunts]
[REINER and EREN grunting]
Bastard! I'll--I'll kill you!
I'll rip you apart!
Explain to me
why we're leaving early.
Ymir. When you changed
back into a human,
d'you have any memory
of the person you ate?
[Gasps]
Huh. No, not really.
We're talking about something
that happened five years ago.
But the way you're asking,
I'm guessing that
it was someone you knew?
[EREN yelling, groaning]
I see. Then I'm, uh,
sorry for not remembering.
[Yelling]
Hey, it's not your
fault that you don't.
It was the same
for Reiner and me.
[YMIR]
Yeah?
[BERTHOLDT] Eren doesn't
remember either.
[YMIR]
Is that how it works?
You hold that against me?
I don't think so.
I mean. I don't know.
Suppose I have to believe you
didn't want to eat anyone.
How, uh, how long were you
wandering outside the walls?
Oh, about sixty years.
Hell on earth.
Every day was like
waking up into a nightmare.
[Gunshot]
Red smoke signal, sir.
The hell?
[Gasps]
Commander Erwin,
we're surrounded!
There is a way around.
Should we head towards it?
[ERWIN] No. We don't
have time for a detour.
We'll forge ahead!
Soldiers! Prepare to fight!
[REINER] For now, we find
a place without Titans!
As far away as possible!
I haven't recovered enough
to outrun these guys.
They surround us,
there's jack shit
my Titan form
can do right now.
Then why the hell
didn't we just wait
for the sun to go down?
[Gasps]
Smoke signals? Did the
Scouts come to save us?
Damn it. That formation
wouldn't work
unless they hoisted a bunch
of horses over the wall.
Who gave that order?
I honestly thought we had
more time than this.
It's gotta be Commander Erwin.
Hard as nails, that one.
[Distant gunshot]
[REINER] Damn.
They're already that close?
It's Eren's fault
for losing his cool.
[YMIR]
Wait. Is she...?
Christa's here.
Reiner! We have
to go back! Now!
Christa's with them!
--What?
--This is our best chance!
You're full of it!
No way you can see that far!
Look, I just know!
Think about it, okay?
She's a big softie, right?
Stupid girl's come
to rescue me! She had to!
Yeah, well so what?
I'm sorry!
It'll have to wait!
[YMIR]
What?
We can't grab her
the way things are now!
There's no way to
bust up that formation!
Another time!
How long you want me to wait?
Maybe I should just hold off
on that until I've been
gobbled up by one of
your warrior pals?
Oh no! I don't think so!
Don't be that way!
Nobody's trying to
trick you, I swear it!
[YMIR]
Prove it, then!
There's no time like
the present, asshole!
Damn you! Get down there
and bring her with us!
I need to see her!
You don't understand.
The way things are going,
will.
[BERTHOLDT]
We can't.
Let it go, Ymir.
Who knows whether
we'll even manage
to survive this. Sorry.
It's just too risky.
Listen to me.
You have my word.
I want her out of this
as much as you do.
Bear with me.
You have to trust us!
This is what's best
for Christa!
Do you understand?
Yes, I understand.
Real question is, do you?
Of course!
All right, then.
Thank you for that.
[YMIR] It's happening again.
I've come so far.
Done so much. And still wound up
falling for my own bullshit.
[MAN 35A]
Well. They look promising.
What about this one?
[MAN 35B]
Mm.
[MAN 35A]
Hello there.
How would you feel about
coming to live with us?
Think of it as the start
of a brand-new life.
Of course, a brand-new life
needs a brand-new name.
Don't you agree?
[YMIR]
Huh?
[YMIR] That day... That was the
first time I lied to myself.
Told myself I had
no say in the matter.
That I never
had a choice. But...
[MAN 35A] It is this Lady Ymir
that inherits the blood
of His Majesty the king.
So long as she graces us
with her presence,
immortality shall be ours.
[Clapping]
[YMIR] To be fair,
it wasn't all that bad.
[Gasps]
[YMIR] My food wasn't cold.
I no longer slept in the dirt.
[SISTER]
Lady Ymir.
[YMIR] Best of all, I knew what
it meant to feel needed.
For the first time in my life,
I actually meant something
to someone else.
That, by far, was more
precious than anything.
Then, one day...
[BELIEVERS holler]
[MAN 35A] It's her fault!
The girl's to blame!
She said the blood of the king
flowed in her veins!
We're only guilty
of believing her!
[YMIR] I was cruelly
reminded that everything
I clung to was an act.
Is that so?
I-I only...
It's true.
I am Ymir!
The king's blood
runs through me!
[BELIEVERS gasp]
[YMIR] Lie once,
the rest follow easy.
[YMIR gasps]
If it saved
their necks, so be it.
Trouble was, things didn't
quite work out that way.
[Breathe rapidly]
[Screams]
Help me!
[Coughs and screams]
Stop this! I'm begging you!
It's not right!
[Squelch]
[YMIR yelps]
[YMIR] That's when I realized.
I'd had it coming all along.
I'd deceived
those gullible bastards,
but that wasn't what I was
being punished for really.
It was for deceiving myself
into thinking
someone needed me.
What else did I expect?
That's what comes of looking
at the world through a veil.
[YMIR TITAN growls]
[ALL gasp]
[MARCEL]
Titan! Run!
[MARCEL grunts]
[MARCEL hollers]
No!
[Screams]
[YMIR gasps]
[YMIR]
When I opened my eyes,
the first thing
I saw was freedom.
The first thing I thought
was if there's
such thing as fate,
she's a fickle little whore.
[Laughs]
Right then and there
I made a vow.
No more deceiving myself.
No more falling
for my own line.
From then on, I'd be real.
[MALE ORDER OF THE WALLS 35A]
So, how did that play out?
[MALE ORDER OF THE WALLS 35B]
Ah, the child was given
the name "Christa Lenz."
Then, she was packed off
to the Cadet Corps.
That is a pity.
Poor wretch. Would've been
better were she never born.
Are you trying
to pick a fight?
All right, sure.
Makes no difference to me.
[YMIR]
And then...
What do we have here?
This your idea
of trying to be nice?
[BOTH gasp]
Well, uh.
[YMIR]
And then I met you.
Immediately, I could tell.
You and I were the same.
You nourished yourself on lies.
Together, we give our hearts!
[CADETS]
Sir!
[YMIR] Here was someone
desperately trying
to convince herself of
something she knew wasn't true.
I get it. Believe me.
And don't worry.
I'm not asking you
to understand.
No. What I want
is very simple.
Just let me be honest
with myself one last time.
That's all.
Let's face it, guys.
I'm the one
best suited for this.
[BERTHOLDT hollers]
What are you doing?
Hey, shut the hell up and
use your head for a second.
In a forest like this I'm the
one who can shine. Right?
[Yells]
[BERTHOLDT] Ymir!
Knock it off! We'll fall!
Do you think
that I give a damn?
I have the advantage.
Any other time you two
would outclass me.
But my Titan form's more agile.
I could leap through
the trees, grab Eren,
and rendezvous with the Scouts
before you knew what hit you.
Wouldn't be that hard.
Either you agree to take
Christa with us today,
right now, or so
help me I will throw
your whole plan out of whack!
Uh! Are you
completely insane?
That doesn't help her!
I thought that
you genuinely cared!
I do. In my way.
If it robs her of a future,
then life's a bitch,
but by god I will live
to see her again!
I've made my peace with
what that says about me.
You guys have no idea
what it's like.
She knows what
a shitty person I am,
but she still
smiles at me. I can't--
Damn it.
[YMIR] Don't be pissed.
I have a fairly decent plan.
Besides, if I stay and fight,
it'll be easier
for you three to get away.
Then again,
if you don't like it,
we can always tear each other
apart like animals!
[SOLDIERS screaming]
[Gasps]
That light.
You saw it, too, huh?
It's coming from the forest!
I think someone's
transforming into a Titan!
We're out of time.
Soldiers, disperse!
The enemy has
assumed Titan form!
Find Eren and
get him out of there!
[SOLDIERS gasp]
[Screams]
Another MP.
[ERWIN]
Battle is not our objective!
Locate, recover, and retreat!
Round up the horses!
Right away, sir!
[HANNES] First thing we do
is pinpoint the enemy
and tell the others!
They're fleeing through the
woods, so stay sharp! Break!
--[MIKASA] Eren.
--[ARMIN] Where are you?
[YMIR TITAN roars]
That's the
scream of a Titan!
It came from just up ahead!
I can see you!
No, wait a second!
It's actually Ymir!
This is her Titan form.
She's one of
the people they took!
What the hell happened?
Where is everybody else?
Is Eren okay?
What about
Bertholdt and Reiner?
So this is Ymir.
Did she assume
Titan form to take on
Reiner and escape?
Ymir! What's the deal?
Did you manage
to get away from them?
What direction did they go?
Give us something
to go on! Anything!
[CONNY]
Say something already!
Come on, ugly!
We're kinda in a rush!
Is she keeping
an eye out for Reiner?
[Gasps]
Something isn't right.
Why--Why is she
looking at us one by one?
[CHRISTA]
Ymir!
There you are!
Thank goodness
you're all right!
[BOTH gasp]
What?
Did she just--?
Ymir, what are you doing?
Don't just stand there!
Move your asses!
[JEAN] She's fast!
We're losing her!
Why would she do that?
What's wrong with you people?
Am I seriously the only one
who saw this coming?
Well, it's clear where
her loyalties are now!
She and Reiner
are on the same side!
We were lured into a trap!
[BERTHOLDT]
Heads up. She's back.
Good.
Oh, no!
[ARMIN] No! They're getting
away with Eren!
[HANNES] Move it!
Get on your damn horses!
This ain't over, you hear me?
I'll get him back
if it costs me my life!
♪ Closing Song ♪